Hi, my name is Don Cole. I'm a PhD
student in the ISC department NC State
University. My research focus on
building a realtime decision support
framework for additive manufacturing
using a diffusion model which is one of
the core algorithm of generative AI.
Laser powder bed fusion is not only for
prototyping but also producing rear
parts in many applications like
aerospace and medical. But the process
is highly sensitive to parameter
settings. So even small deviation from
the optimal setting can cause serious
quality problem and defects may still
occur even on the optimal setting as
defect formation is some stochastic. My
work goes one step further from the
previous studies not only to predict
what may happen next but also to support
the real time decision on whether the
ongoing printing process should continue
or stop. For this I used the paragan
data set released by okage in 2023 which
contains multimodel information aligned
across space and time including postmelt
post record images in sich environmental
signals and so on. What I need to
generate is a postmelt images and other
modalities are being used as a
conditioner information. I propose a
framework consisting of three
components. The first piece is
generator. It is a diffusion model that
forecast the next layer postmelt images
based on previous object layer. The
second piece is evaluator a CNN based
defect predictor that takes generated
output and predict the corresponding
defect rate. The last piece is the
decision engine which use the predicted
defect distribution to make go or no
decision in real time. Based on this
setup, I can generate multiple layer uh
samples, evaluate each of them, and
finally estimate the defect
distribution. Now, it allows me to make
answer the aware decisions. The result
show that my model generate high quality
samples with structure and texture close
to the ground truth. And since the
evaluator estimate defect rate for
different classes of defect, the
framework can now flag risky regions
based on a userdefined threshold.
This figure show the defect distribution
of class 2 3 and 11 at layer number 100.
In this example, if the 100 real
printing yields a second class defect of
0.230,
then it suggests to stop the printing as
this defect will be propagated and make
the process worse.
My work is a unified framework for
real-time riskaware LPBF monitoring by
using generative AI and also even the
first diffusion model built upon the
paragraph data set. In the future I want
to improve the generalization across
different build machine and connect all
the uh forecast to the finer part
quality. Thanks for your time and
support.